Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  - Incoming
    - He - Hi, 1887-1896 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Hewes, Anna Lathrop, Tel. birthday greetings, Aug 23, 1888
      - Hill, H.C., ALS kindergartens, etc., Nov 20, 1890
      - Hill, Thomas, ALS congratulations, Mar 5, 1896
    - Ho, 1872-1896 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Hodges, Myrtis Charles, ALS personal news, Oct 16, 1895
      - Hodges, Myrtis Charles, ALS personal news, Mar 10, ny
      - Hoffman, J. W., ALS asking for photo of Leland Jr., Aug 3, 1893
      - Hoitt, Ira G., ALS congratulations on successful settlement of suit, Mar 3, 1896
      - Holtzman, R.O., note re sale of Washington house (?), 1893
      - Holtzman, R.O., Tel. congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - Hooker, J. (Maj. Gen'l.), ALS arrangements for visit to Sacramento, Sep 19, 1872
      - Hooker, May Osgood, ANS on successful settlement of suit, Mar 1896
      - Hopkins, E.W., Tel. congratulations on Ross decision, Jul 1 1895
      - Hopkins Seaside Lab (Stanford Boarding Club), Tel. on successful settlement of suit, July 1, 1895
      - Houghton, Mr. and Mrs. J.F., ALS on successful settlement of suit, Mar 2, 1896
      - Houston, Mrs. F. H., ALS naming their baby boy "Leland Stanford Houston", July 31, 1893
    - Hu - Hy, 1892-1903 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Hubbard, S. Isabelle, ALS re receipt of $150 for memorial, Jan 11, 1893
      - Hubbard, S. Isabelle, ALS with congratulations, Mar 5, 1896
      - Hughes, Toby, ALS re photo of Gen. Grant, Dec 17, 1903
      - Hull, Lizzie, ALS re sending her Leland Jr.'s letters, July 10, 1884
      - Hull, Lizzie, ALS re thinking of her and hopes to see her on return, Mar Mar 15, 1885
      - Hulme, Edward M., ALS and ptd. poem "In Memoriam L. Stanford, Jr.", Mar 15, 1896
      - Hurley, W.J., ALS re: verses, Dec 28, 1893
      - Hutchings, Mary C., ALS sketch of life of J. L. Stanford by Mrs. John A. Logan, Apr 20, 1892
      - Huul, Catharine, ALS social note, undated
      - Hyatt, Francis A., ALS classmate of L.Stanford writes to congratulate her on Judge Ross' decision, July 5, 1895
      - Hyde, James M.,ALS is grateful for his education, Nov 14, 1894
      - Hyde, W.F., ALS re lack of drinking water on the Quad, Feb 14, 1898
    - Ingalls, Ethel, (see also Blair, Ethel Ingalls), 1891-1893 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - ALS congratulations on opening of university, Oct 17, 1891
      - ALS inquires after Leland's health, Jan 13, 1893
      - ALS personal, Oct 3, 1893
      - ALS sending some verses, undated
    - I, 1893-1902 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - I[illegible], [Geo.] H., ALS from England, personal, Mar 11, 1893
      - S. Ikeda and Co., ALS to Bertha Berner, re bronzes Mrs. Stanford bought in Japan, 1902 Aug 23 and Sep 1
      - Iles, Ida M. F., ALS asking for a favor [missing page 1], undated
      - Irish, John P., ALS congratulations, June 30, 1895
      - Irish, John P., ALS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
    - Jordan, David Starr
      Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931
      - 1891-1895 (Box 6, Folder 29)
        - ALS to Camille Leach. Reorganization of Roble Hall., Oct 23-24, 1891
        - ALS re. first commencement and graduates., June, 24, 1892
        - ALS re. university affairs; visit to Hopkins Seaside Laboratory; new Univ. of Chicago; marriage of Chas. Edward Hodges., Aug 1, 1892
        - ALS. sympathy note re. death of Leland Stanford., June 25, 1893
        - ALS. re. attack on Mrs. Stanford in the Examiner., July 26, 1893
        - TLS. with encls. re. addition to "The Camp.", May 27, 1893
        - ALS. Re. decision of Court., June 29, 1895
        - ALS. Number of students in university not being increased., July 3, 1895
        - ALS. Must trust loyalty of students., Aug 4, 1895
        - TEL. Congratulations from students and professors., Oct 16, 1895
        - ALS [draft]. Raising registration fees., circa 1895
      - 1895-1900 (Box 6, Folder 30)
        - Telegram. Congratulations., March 2, 1896
        - ALS. Invitation to come see the Faculty., March 4, 1896
        - TLS. re. separate county school district for Stanford., Mar 5, 1898
        - Telegram. Unauthorized statement in Chronicle., Mar 23, 1898
        - TLS. Mr. Cox associated Stanford with Summer School in Pacific Grove., March 23, 1898
        - AL. Trustees., May 9, 1899
        - ALS [with enclosure: Mr. Adams to Dr. Jordan]. Mr. Adams, farmer; leasing land on Stanford property., May 13, 1899
        - ALS. re. his visits to eastern universities., March 17, 1900
        - ALS. "Barbara Jordan Library of Birds and Trees" in memory of daughter., 18-Sep-00
        - TL Ross a shameless adventurer; would treat Howard as gently as we can, 21-Nov-00
        - TN Ross affair; with note in J.L.Stanford's hand, 10-Dec-00
      - 1901 (Box 6, Folder 31)
        - ALS. Receiving letters from Murren; and Matthew Arnold poem., August 4, 1901
        - TLS. re. location of engineering bldgs., 30-Oct-01
        - TLS. Mr. Lathrop's desire to not buy from California dealers., 6-Nov-01
        - ALS. Purchase of Tonometer, 12-Nov-01
        - ANS. re. Prof. Newcomer's ode for the the Church dedication., 15-Nov-01
        - TLS. expense account for the new Chemical Laboratory of the University of Berlin., 15-Nov-01
        - TLS. re enclosed letter (from J. Abramowsky wanting to be agent for J. L. Stanford in purchasing Mexian relics), 15-Nov-01
        - ALS. Thanks for kind notes., 16-Nov-01
        - ALS. re. Mrs. Stanford's gifts to the university., 11-Dec-01
        - ALS. re. Schmidt affair., 12-Dec-01
        - ALS. Christmas greetings., 16-Dec-01
      - 1902 Jan-Mar (Box 6, Folder 32)
        - ALS. re. Prof. Pease and the dept. of Latin., 11-Jan-02
        - TLS and encl. re. Student Guild and student guild hospital., 16-Jan-02
        - TLS. What it takes to build up a real University as opposed to a first-rate college., 6-Feb-02
        - ALS. re. trip East., 11-Feb-02
        - Telegram. Leaving for New York., March 1, 1902
        - ALS. re. German architect, Dr. Max Jaughaundel (?), March 19, 1902
        - TLS. re. gift of medallion commemorating signing of treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo., 22-Mar-02
        - TLS. Real University work requires buildings and equipment., 26-Mar-02
        - TLS with encl. re. Jordan's letter to Rev. Heber Newton., 27-Mar-02
        - TLS. re. Mr. Farquhar and Mr. Stanley-Brown visiting Stanford., 31-Mar-02
      - 1902 Apr-Oct (Box 6, Folder 33)
        - ALS. re. performance of Antigone; law professors "stolen" from Stanford by Univ. of Chicago., 20-Apr-02
        - ALS. re. another professor "bought" by the Univ. of Chicago., April 30, 1902
        - ALS. re. Prof. Pease affair., May 27, 1902
        - TLS [with enclosure from Mr. Soule] re. increase in Mr. Soule's salary., May 28, 1902
        - ALS. re. death of Mr. Nash., June 10, 1902
        - ALS. Greetings on way to Somoa., June 12, 1902
        - ALS. re. address to Trustees., 4-Oct-02
        - TLS. re. demolition of Art bldg. given by Mrs. Barron., 9-Oct-02
        - TLS. 1902 re. letter of enclosure: espression of good will., Oct 13
        - TLS. re. needs of Columbia College., 14-Oct-02
      - 1902 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 34)
        - ALS. re. conduct on campus; morals; control of Roble Hall., 5-Nov-02
        - TLS. re. bldg. for YWCA., 6-Nov-02
        - TLS. re. conduct in fraternities and sororities., 12-Nov-02
        - TLS. Acquisition of testing machine for timber [with 2 enclosures: C.B. Wing to Jordan and F. E. Olmsted to Wing]., 12-Nov-02
        - TLS. re. Museum room in new science bldg., 13-Nov-02
        - TLS. Complete list of members of the Faculty. [List not with letter], 13-Dec-02
      - 1903-1904 (Box 6, Folder 35)
        - TLS. re. needs of the Engineering depts., 20-Mar-03
        - ALS. re. Dr. Stillman, Dr. Marx, other faculty matters, new baby, 2-Mar-04
        - ALS. re. controversy over location of Junior Ball., 11-Mar-04
        - Memo re. use of Leland Stanford Jr. Scholarship., July 16, 1904
        - TLS. re. Rev. R. J. Campbell., July 22, 1904
        - TLS. re. Law School., July 26, 1904
        - TLS. re. Law School., July 27, 1904
        - ALS. re. appt. of Prof. William James., 11-Aug-04
        - ALS. Entrance examinations beginning; Horace Davis letters., 25-Aug-04
        - TLS. Horace Davis letters., 25-Aug-04
        - ALS. re. Thos Welton Stanford endowed chair in psychology., 5-Sep-04
        - ALS. re size of University, building plan, difficulties for the faculty, 11-Sep-04
    - J, 1886-1896 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - James, Charles, ALS. sending book on economic education, Jan 29 1886
      - Jay, John, ALS. thanks for the California wine, May 5, 1890
      - Jaywith (?), C. A., ALS. congratulations, religious sentiments, June 30, 1895
      - Johnson, E., ALS congratulations, July 2, 1895
      - Jones, Mrs. C. L., ALS. offers her services unpaid as matron of Roble Hall, July 4, 1895
      - Jones, Frank, telegram. congratulations, March 3, 1896
      - Jones, Georgina, ALS. thanks for flowers, praises the University, undated
      - Judson, Albert L., ALS. request for employment with Mrs. Stanford., Aug 7 ?, 1893
      - Judson, Albert L., ALS. re. postponement on payment of his loan from Mrs. Stanford., Sep 27, 1893
      - Judson, Maria, ALS. congratulations, news of family and friends, March 2, 1896
    - Ka - Ki, 1884-1902 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Kappa Kappa Gamma, telegram [no signature]. Congratulations, March 2, 1896
      - Keane, John, TLS Congratulations, March 9, 1896
      - Kearney, Denis, ALS would like to get back his letters to Sen. Stanford, July 8, 1893
      - Keesling, F.V., ALS re. his history of the passage of the constitutional amendment., 27-Aug-02
      - Kellogg, Martin, ALS congratulations, March 3, 1896
      - Kellogg, Peter, ALS congratulations, March 2, 1896
      - Keyes, Charles, TLS congratulations, March 3, 1896
      - King, Patrick M., ALS encloses sonnet written in their honor, July 10, 1891
      - Kinkeed, Lizzie, ALS plea to help a friend of hers, July 13, 1893
      - Kinne, Elizabeth D'Arcy, ALS thanks for donation to Woman's Relief Corps, Sep 8, 1887
      - Kip, Wm. Ingraham to Mrs. Hopkins, ALS please convey our sorrow to Mrs. Stanford, March 14, 1884
    - Kn - Ku, 1893-1902 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Knott, Regina, ALS thanks for photograph, undated
      - Knox, Mrs. G. R., ALS congratulations, news of her father A. L. Downer, March 6, 1896
      - Kohl, Mary, ALS appreciation for kindness on death of her father, January 16, 1894
      - Kohl, Mrs. William, 2 telegram congratulations, June 29, 1895; March 3, 1896
      - Krum, Mrs. Hetty, ALS condolences on death of Leland, July 12, 1893
      - Kruttschnitt, J., TLS congratulations, March 2, 1896
      - Kruttschnitt, J., TLS enclosing annual RR pass, May 18, 1898
      - Kuma, T., ALS and 2 encls. encloses his speech and list of Japanese students, 23-Dec-02
    - Lathrop, Charles G.
      - 1893-1895 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - TL re. furniture., Aug 12, 1893
        - TL re. payment to workers at Vina; other financial matters, Aug 16, 1893
        - TL re. payment to workers at VIna., Aug 16, 1893
        - TL Payments from estate., Aug 18, 1893
        - TL Sign checks for wages to be paid from estate, Aug 18, 1893
        - TL re financial transaction over tax on brandy, Aug 22, 1893
        - TLS re. $20,000 loan made to J.L. Stanford by the Nevada Bank., Sep 6, 1893
        - TL Withdrawal of brandy., Sep 6, 1893
        - TL Payment to Charley Wooster., Sep 6, 1893
        - TL re. lease of Gwin Ranch to J.M. Stora. [probably J.M. Stone], Sep 11, 1893
        - Telegram re. court decision., Oct 12, 1895
      - 1901 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Telegram re. Mexican Int. RR., 6-Aug-01
        - TLS re. Pacific Improvement Co.; finance; labor troubles in city., 7-Aug-01
        - TLS Salviati and Co., 4-Nov-01
        - ALS re. Mr. Loeser's request for soil fill for his campus residence., 14-Nov-01
        - TLS re. carpentry work on the Natural Sciences bldg., 19-Nov-01
        - TLS Mexican International RR 4% bonds., 11-Dec-01
        - TEL [With 2 enclosures] Price of Mexican International RR Bonds., 16-Dec-01
        - TLS re. mosaics in Church and museum; financial matters., 19-Dec-01
        - TLS re. construction of Memorial Church; opening of [Stanford?] Inn., 23-Dec-01
        - TL Financial., 26-Dec-01
        - Coded Telegram, 26-Dec-01
        - Telegram [to Bertha Berner]. Success of previous telegram., 27-Dec-01
        - TLS financial; personal; J. L. Stanford's operation for wens., 27-Dec-01
        - TLS Amount in banks., 30-Dec-01
        - Telegram Manhattan American Cotton., 30-Dec-01
      - 1902 Jan-Apr (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Telegram. Measurements for bedroom., 14-Jan-02
        - TLS financial matters; Memorial Church construction and other construction on campus., 14-Jan-02
        - TLS window screens, leave terrace contract until you return, certificate of deposit received, 16-Jan-02
        - Telegram re. draperies, 17-Jan-02
        - Telegram re. deed from Mrs. McCann., 20-Jan-02
        - Coded Telegram, 20-Jan-02
        - TLS Financial., 20-Jan-02
        - telegrams (some in code) re financial matters, Paoletti drawings, business travel, Jan 21-Feb 8, 1902
        - TLS [with 2 enclosures] re. financial matters., 20-Feb-02
        - TLS re. inspection visit to Vina Ranch; construction on campus; Madrono Hall., 18-Apr-02
        - TLS re. copies of cablegrams involving Salviati and Co., April 29, 1902
      - 1902 May-Sep (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - TLS personal; Ah Wing returned., May 1, 1902
        - TLS Hawaiian curios; Heber Newton; mosaics; construction on campus; opinion on Jordan; Memorial Church., May 8, 1902
        - TLS re. Memorial Church; dismissal of Prof. Pease; water carnival on Lake Lagunita., May 16, 1902
        - TLS Assuming power of attorney over Charles through Bank of California., July 25, 1902
        - TLS Leasing of land for Phi Kappa Psi., 11-Sep-02
        - TLS Wholesale Druggists convention visiting Memorial Church., 22-Sep-02
        - TLS re. purchase of Japanese bronze lanterns., 22-Sep-02
        - TLS re. administration of museum collections., 23-Sep-02
      - 1902 Oct-Nov (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - TLS re. payment of Jennie S. Lathrop tuition bill., 6-Oct-02
        - Tel. re hauling her RR car east, 6-Oct-02
        - TLS re. Stanford's Albany, New York, property; bronze doors for church., 7-Oct-02
        - TLS re. contracts (Salviati and Co.) and agreements (Dunsmuir and Pacific Improvement Co.), 8-Oct-02
        - TLS re. Stanford private RR car; construction on campus; Sacramento Stanford residence; Memorial Church., 9-Oct-02
        - Telegram Lowest estimate for new house., 12-Oct-02
        - TLS re. dogs at Palo Alto residence; J. L. Stanford's will; possible rental of some Palo Alto property., 13-Oct-02
        - TLS re. Pacific Improvement Co. finances., 14-Oct-02
        - TLS re. additions to Memorial Church; Memorial Court; sale of Stock Farm horses; issue re. use of Assembly Hall; construction of the gymnasium., 21-Oct-02
        - TLS re granite pedestals for statues in Memorial Court., 23-Oct-02
        - TLS personal; financial., 24-Oct-02
        - Telegram re. Scribners and Sons., 27-Oct-02
        - TLS Book publishers; personal., 27-Oct-02
        - TLS Lamps; furniture for Memorial Church., 28-Oct-02
        - TLS with encl. Mr. I. W. Hellman and last address by Mrs. Stanford; personal., 29-Oct-02
        - TLS re. lamps, financial matters, 3-Nov-02
        - Telegram re. lamps., undated
    - Lathrop, Henry C., 1892 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - ALS re. illness of Mr. Nash in London., June 16, 1892
      - ALS re. Illness of Nash., June 17, 1892
      - ALS re. illness of Nash; family matters., June 28, 1892
      - ALS re. money received, Nash recovering, July 5, 1892
      - ALS re. illness of Nash; family matters., July 6, 1892
      - ALS re. recovery of Nash., July 11, 1892
      - ALS re. don't come until the weather is cooler, Aug 19, 1892
    - Lathrop family, 1890-1905 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Lathrop, Ariel, telegram does not accept position, May 17, 1895
      - Lathrop, E.B.C., ALS family history and list of articles presented to Museum (incl. Lathrop family tree), undated
      - Lathrop, Elsie K., ALS requesting assistance in getting an education, 10-Sep-05
      - Lathrop, Mrs. Jane A., invitation to Jane A. Lathrop's funeral in Albany, NY, Sep 4 1882
      - Lathrop, Jennie S.,ANS personal, Oct 28, 1894
      - Lathrop, Leland, ALS death of Aunt Anna, Aug 21, 1892
      - Rowell, Betsy Lathrop, ALS sends pictures of her children, Nov 2, 1890
    - Lawton, 1902-1904 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Lawton, Jennie Lathrop ALS re. article on Lathrop genealogy in Albany newspaper., 1-Oct-02
      - Lawton, Jennie Lathrop ALS couldn't visit because of illness, undated
      - Lawton, Geo. P. ALS re. Shields genealogy, May 3, 1902
      - Lawton, Geo. P. ALS re. admission of son to Stanford University, 7-Mar-04
    - Leib, Samuel F., 1900-1903 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - A.N.S. and cvr. re: will, 1900-03-17
      - TLS re trustee matter, water in a field, March 21, 1900
      - TLS re new well, March 24, 1900
      - TLS re his schedule, March 30, 1900
      - TLS re unnamed business matter, November 20, 1901
      - TLS re carrying out her wishes in regard to grants, December 12, 1901
      - ALS re business matters, glad she is feeling well, 1901-12-30
      - TLS re purchasing Gill law library, March 17, 1902
      - TLS re purchasing Gill law library, March 22, 1902
      - TLS re Gill law library, getting power from Portola Reservoir, his success in different legal case, March 26, 1902
      - TLS re purchase of Gill law library, April 9, 1902
      - TLS re received her instructions re burials in arboretum, July 14, 1902
      - TLS [w/ enclosure: Leib to Charles Lathrop, Aug. 18, 1902 and letter to Leib, Aug., 1902] re sale of land in Alameda County, August 18, 1902
      - ALS re visiting University on Oct. 6, 1902-09-25
      - ALS re praise for her address to trustees, 1902-10-21
      - ALS re death of Mr. Bowman, university running well, December 2, 1903
    - Lippincott, S.J. (Grace Greenwood), 1885-1896 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - ALS and cvr. visit to Florence, house where Leland Jr. died (Hotel de La Paix), hardships, daughter ready for operatic debut but no money, Jan 1 1885
      - ALS asks job for husband, Feb 22, 1885
      - ALS Annie to make debut in Trieste, Apr 14, 1885
      - ALS photos of Stanfords, Aug 1, 1885
      - ALS earthquake, University, Annie's illness, Feb 23, 1887
      - ALS her proposal for biography of Leland Jr., has adopted Christian Science, Jan 18, 1888
      - ALS personal, Dec 8, 1889
      - ALS encloses note from Mrs. Burnett, Mar 24, 1893
      - ALS her health, daughter's marriage, praise for Jane, Nov 27, 1894
      - ALS recommends spiritual healer Miss Susie Clark, Feb 3, 1896
      - ALS congratulations on court verdict, March 3, 1896
    - Little Sisters of the Poor, Washington, DC, 1893-1894 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Logan, John A. Jr., 1886-1893 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - ALS personal greetings, Feb 2 1892
      - LS sending her clipping, hopes Senator is better, Jan 16, 1893
      - ALS avoids stock speculation and politics, Feb 8, 1893
    - Logan, Mary S. (Mrs. John A. Logan, Sr.), 1886-1893 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - ALS Gen. Logan suffering from rheumatism, charity affair, Dec l9, 1886
      - charity for hospital, Dec 1886?
      - recovering from accident (stepped on by horse), son in Ohio, Aug 24, 1887
      - thanks for flowers, anniversary of her husband's death, Dec 25, 1887
      - holding "Garden Fete" for Garfield Hospital at her home, May 12, 1890
      - card hopes to see her soon, undated
      - introducing Albert Hall, undated
    - La, 1889-1896 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Lachlan, J. M., ALS has sent case of wine, Aug 26, 1889
      - Lane, [S. C.], ALS congratulations, March 4, 1896
      - Lansing, Mr. and Mrs. Abraham, Calling card. pencil note on back: "Doctor says Mama has intermittent fever has not yet been out of bed today", undated
      - Lansing, [?] P., Telegram Congratulations., March 2, 1896
      - Lansing, Gerrit, Calling cards., undated
      - Lansing, Mary, ALS re grief at loss of her son, Feb 25, ?
      - Lansing, Mary, please come to Century Club meetings, undated
      - Larger, Edward, telegram congratulations, March 20, 1896
      - Largez, Edward, ALS personal greetings, thanks for assistance in getting position, Feb 9, 1896
      - Latham, Mollie, ALS letter of sympathy on death of Gov. Stanford, Jul 9, ny
      - Laurie, Annie (The Examiner), ALS [with enclosure: Letter from Stanford student with praise for the Stanfords and the University], undated
    - Le - Li, 1890-1896 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Leach, Camilla, ALS re Roble Hall management, Oct 21, 1891
      - Leach, Camilla to D. S. Jordan, ALS is resigning her position, Oct 23, 1891
      - Ledyard, Dr. F. K., ALS letter of praise, June 4th, 1895
      - Leech, Samuel, ALS congratulations, Stanford a great man, March 14, 1896
      - Lemmon, Mr. and Mrs. J.G., ALS support for her cause, plan to give addition to botanic collection of Pacific Coast conifers, July 12, 1895
      - Lemmon, Mr. and Mrs. J.G., ALS Jane as a notable woman, invitation to their home, Feb 8, 1896
      - Leonard, Elizabeth, ALS re Lathrop family items she has, Oct 20, 1890
      - Leonard, [M.] Helena, ALS recommends Berkshire Inn, Nov 26?
      - Liegenfuss, C.O., ALS congratulations, Mar 2, 1896
      - Livingston, Frances, ALS thoughts on her bereavement, Nov 30, 1893
    - Lo - Lu, 1888-1903 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Loeb, Wm. Jr. (sec. to Theodore Roosevelt), LS thanks from President, May 30, 1903
      - Loeb, Wm. Jr., TLS and cvr. thanks for copies of her addresses, July 30, 1903
      - Loeser, Robert M., ALS re soil for his lot on campus, 1901-11-13
      - Loomis, R.A., Tel. congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Loranger, Mrs. F., ALS loss of loved ones is greater sorrow than life of poverty, Feb 14, 1896
      - Lothrop, Mrs. Harriet C., ALS re Lothrop genealogy, 1902-12-12
      - Lothrop, Harriett M., ALS not embittered by her lack of support, has sold publishing company, March 22, 1894
      - Loubat, Joseph Florimond, duc de, ALS books, etc. for L.S.J.U., prizes established, Sep 25, l892
      - Louchard, Alice J. et. al., ALS thank you from students of Prof. Elwood's Singing School in Menlo Park, Dec 28, 1888
      - Loveland, Jane E., ALS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Lusk, F. C., ALS received RR pass, congratulations, offers assistance at Vina, January 5, 1895
    - Incoming: McCarthy, Helena, 1893-1896 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - ALS social news (Mrs. Hearst, the Leiter's, Clevelands), November 12, 1893
      - ALS Christmas greetings, Dec 21, 1894
      - ALS encloses clipping [Washington Evening Star May 1, 1895], May 3, 1895
      - ALS thanks for kind thoughts, Mrs. Stewart's bicycle riding, Aug 1, 1895
      - ALS, March 4, 1896
      - ALS brother John, congratulations on government suit, Mar 4, 1896
    - Incoming: McCarthy, John B., 1893-1896 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - ALS portraits and statues being shipped, July 27, 1893
      - ALS son born Wednesday morning, named him Leland Stanford McCarthy, hopes to continue as her friend, July 28, 1893
      - ALS re published Memorial Addresses on Leland Stanford, Oct 1, 1894
      - ALS sending photo of son, Jan 1, 1895
      - ALS congratulations on Government suit, Mar 2 1896
      - Fragment., Dec 19, ny
    - Incoming: McIntyre, H. W., 1893 (Box 7, Folder 21)